DEVOPS ENGINEER

Summary

Around 4 years of Experience with Configuration Management, Build, Deploy, Release Management, and Quality Assurance. Good understanding of principles and best practices of Software Configuration Management (SCM) in agile and scrum methodologies. Experience in branching, tagging and maintaining version across environments using SCM tools like GIT on UNIX and knowledge on TFS a windows environment. Hands-on experience working with configuration management tools like chef and Ansible. Created SCM Process, policies, procedures and Release Notes to follow Development and allow QA teams to Release or Deploy good quality product for enterprise. Hands-on experience in using IDE such as Visual Studio, Eclipse, and experience working with Artifact management tools like NEXUS, JFROG Strong experience with CI (Continuous Integration) and CD (Continuous Deployment) methodologies with Jenkins. Experience in working with Docker container images managed in Docker trusted registry(DTR). Experienced in using Build Automation tool MAVEN and working knowledge of other build tools like MS Build. Good understanding of services PaaS, SaaS and IaaS. Experienced in working with cloud-based technology Red hat openshift enterprise (OSE V2& OSE V3.2, V3.7) and also knowledge on octopus deploy Experience working with content management platform which is Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) version 6.1&6.2 Experiences working with backend services in spring boot and JBoss applications, and also working with UI applications Angular and Nodejs. worked on building microservices and web applications. Hands-on experience creating and managing various development and build platforms, and deployment strategies. Experienced in bug tracking systems such as Rally. Excellent experience in documenting and automating build and release process. Worked closely with Development teams and collaborated to accomplish their application to be automated and deployed.

• GIT, TFS, SVN

- Languages/Scripts: Javascript, HTML, Bash, shell scripting and power shell.
- Continuous integration Tools: MAVEN, Jenkins, XL deploy, XL Release, Nexus, Docker (DTR), Jfrog, Openshift Enterprise(OSE V2, V3.2, V3.7), Ansible, Kubernetes. Selenium
- Operating Systems: UNIX/LINUX, Windows
- Web Technologies: Java Web Services, Soap UI, Rest, Springboot, JBoss.
- CM Tools: Jboss Apache Web Server 1.x/2.0, JBOSS EAP servers 6.2/6.4, Tomcat, Eclipse, Adobe experience
- manager (AEM), chef, Ansible

Experience

DevOps Engineer 10/2016 to Current Nj, NJ

- As a member of DevOps group, redefined processes and implemented tools for software builds source control, and release tracking and reporting, on UNIX platform.
- Responsible for Development, QA, SYSTEM, UAT, STAGING, BREAKFIX, PRODUCTION Builds and deployment environment setup.
- Builds and deploys Java application in WebLogic Server, JBoss app server EAP and APACHE web servers.
- Experienced working with java spring boot applications and also on web services SOAP and REST API.
- Assist with maintaining current build systems, developed build scripts, and maintained source control in GIT and SVN Responsible for CI environments (Jenkins, Nexus, Sonar).
- Experience working with Docker container.
- Developed build scripts to build Docker images and deployed to Application servers via Docker trusted registry.
- Used kubernetes for container orchestration in openshift platform to deploy pods which contains docker containers running on a node.
- Worked with pods, services, persistence volume claims, Replication controllers which are kubernetes components hosted on an openshift platform and also worked with Redhat Openshift enterprise (OSE2.0, OSE3.1, and OSE3.2) versions.
- Also migrated the apps from V2 to V3.
- Collaborated with team members to create Adobe experience manager AEM (6.0,6.1&6.2) instances which is content management tool upon application requirements.
- Responsible for installation of monitoring tools like Dynatrace and Newrelic on different environments.
- Worked closely with Dual data center and Responsible for configuring VIPS, F5 load balancing and requesting firewalls.
- Involved in Infrastructure Collaboration with dev teams guiding them in the desired way.
- Enforced automation in build and deployment procedures, executed code builds and deployment activities.
- Environment: Chef, Ansible, GIT, Subversion (SVN), Openshift enterprise OSE, Jenkins, Java/J2EE, MAVEN, Nexus, Adobe experience manager(AEM), Shell Scripts, Bash scripts, Linux (RHEL), Apache web servers.

DevOps Engineer 09/2015 to 10/2016 Applied Systems, Inc.

Build and Release Engineer 03/2012 to 02/2013 Booz Allen Hamilton Inc. Portland

- Installed and supported code migration processes using Subversion and CI with Jenkins.
- Worked with Architects on SDLC process being the owner of post-development Environments Source code configuration tools Subversion and GIT used for different projects.
- Assisted in and supported migration of code and binary packages into Enterprise repository, working closely with sustain teams to maintain branch structure.
- Helped resolve branching and merge conflicts and other issues that developer's encountered while utilizing Subversion.
- Assisted build engineers and developers in doing daily and weekly builds.
- Resolved issues related to build failures like view, build script problems and syntax errors.
- Coordinating resources by working closely with Project Manager's for release and Project Manager for all the Operational Projects Carried

Deployments and builds on various environments using continuous integration tool.

- Developed and implemented software release management for the release of Web Applications.
- Used Shell to automate the deployment process.
- Coordinated all the IT projects successfully by resolving release interdependencies.

Devop's Engineer

- for a team that involved different development teams and multiple simultaneous software releases and implemented Continuous Integration Process.
- Maintaining the source code (source code management) and day to day bug tracking.
- Configured the build and deploy flow to Middleware .Net and Java environments using Jenkins, MS build tool and deployment tool octopus deploy.
- Responsible for maintenance of Team foundation server 2015(TFS) Source control.
- Collaborated in Upgrading source control, TFS 2013 to TFS 2015 and Octopus Deploy 2.0 to Octopus deploy 3.0.
- Configured Jenkins for java applications to build the artifacts and deploy into Nexus artifactory repository.
- Worked on MS build for C# applications and Jenkins for Java(J2EE) applications to automate build process.
- Responsible for maintaining the CI environments (Jenkins, Sonatype nexus).
- Participated in application release with developer, DBA, QA and project management teams.
- Worked with build engineers and developers in doing daily and weekly builds.
- Resolved issues related to build failures like view, build template problems and syntax errors.
- Environment: Team foundation server 2015, Subversion (SVN), GIT, MS build, Jenkins, .Net/C#, Java/J2EE, MAVEN, Nexus, Power Shell Scripts, Windows.

Education and Training

Masters: Computer Engineering May 2015 Wright state university City, State Computer Engineering GPA: 3.1/4

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics and Communication Engineering MAY 2013 Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, A.P Electronics and Communication Engineering GPA: 3.2/4

Skills

Adobe, APACHE, Apache Web Server 1.x, content management, DBA, Eclipse, firewalls, Java, Javascript, JBOSS, LINUX, C#, Middleware, Redhat, Shell Scripts, shell scripting, Tomcat, UNIX, Web Applications, web servers, WebLogic